

### Davidson Ekpokpobe

Full stack Developer

Full Stack Developer with nearly five years of experience in banking, fintech, and project management. Completed over 20 projects, reducing issue resolution time by 30% and improving system performance by 25%. Skilled at breaking down complex problems and creating efficient algorithms.

davidsonekpokpobe@gmail.com

Lagos, Nigeria

in linkedin.com/in/davidson-ekpokpobe

### +2348058783359

devon1910.github.io/Portfolio-/

github.com/devon1910

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Developer Dash360

02/2023 - Present Texas, USA

Dash360 specializes in the design, development, and implementation of project controls systems for big science and technology projects.

- Revolutionized client reporting efficiency by 80% through the strategic use of data projection and optimization of stored procedures, cutting down report generation time from 25 minutes to 5 minutes.
- Implemented a custom Dev Express Data Grid enabling data export to Word and Excel for 17+ clients.
- Bolstered system efficiency by optimizing the logic for 1000+ resource code calculation.
- Rearchitected and rebuilt the client report using lazy loading, boosting load speed by 40%.

### **Back End Developer** Sterling Bank

10/2021 - 02/2023 Lagos, Nigeria

One of the Top 10 biggest enterprise banks in Nigeria.

- Refactored transaction flow APIs on Slick-Hustle, a fintech app, eliminating ambiguities and removing the cash payment option to ensure 100% commission goes to the bank.
- Orchestrated the development of scalable admin dashboards enabling the support team to view and update customer information, generate transaction reports and display system metrics for 10000+ users.
- Architected the flow and design of the Web APIs powering 'Booky'. A Books management catalogue for 30+ clients.

### **EDUCATION**

## Computer Science Covenant University

09/2017 - 09/2021

Ogun State, Nigeria.

 Data Structures & Algorithms, Software Engineering, Object Oriented Programming, Artificial Intelligence.

### **SKILLS**



### PERSONAL PROJECTS

Crendly (04/2022 - Present)

- Crendly uses innovative technology to increase credit availability for more than 500 people in emerging markets.
- Engineered on a scalable microservices architecture using .NET for backend services and React for the frontend, integrated with PostgreSQL databases, and successfully hosted on Microsoft Azure.
- Developed and deployed an advanced wallet and fees computation service, successfully processing more than 250 transactions, which enhanced financial transparency and reduced processing time by 25%.
- Azure service Bus implementation for effective communication between all 10 microservices.

### Referral Hub (02/2024 - 03/2024) 🗹

- A robust WEB API for Referral codes Generation that boasts of all key and nice-to-have features of a Standard WEB API.
- CLEAN Architecture and CQRS design pattern to facilitate seamless Scaling and Testing.
- Endpoints security for Authorization and Authentication via JSON Web Tokens.
- Role Management system for over 1,000 identity users, ensuring secure and efficient user access control.

Bloggy (09/2020 - 02/2020) 🗹

- Blog Management site with over 200 entries i still use myself for documenting my learnings each day.
- Coded in Node, Express, EJS and MongoDB for data capture.

### LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE

Led the development team in building the APIs for 'EronVille', a real estate site connecting realtors with tenants, from conception to launch.

### **INTERESTS**

Mentoring Blogging

Open Source Contribution